这里是全宇宙最强大的力量吗？
101 Is this the greatest power in the universe?
前情提要
一个在逃的时间犯在杀害我们的时间卫士
MOBIUS: A fugitive Variant's been killing our Minutemen.
不管这个时间犯是谁 我们一直找不到他
Whoever this Variant is,  we haven't been able to find him.
时间变异管理局和阿斯加德的众神 是一路货色
LOKI: The Time Variance Authority and the gods of Asgard, one and the same.
醉心于权力 却无视真相
Drunk with power, blinded to the truth.
时间守护者监控着这个案件的每个环节
The Time-Keepers are monitoring every aspect of this case.
他藏在末日里
He's hiding in apocalypses.
所以你就是时间变异管理局找来 追捕我的那个笨蛋
HUNTER B-15: You're the fool the TVA brought in to hunt me down.
应该是我吧
Me, I presume.
我要推翻时间守护者
I'm going to overthrow the Time-Keepers.
我对统治时间变异管理局毫无兴趣
I'm not interested in ruling the Time Variance Authority.
我说出去了
HUNTER C-20: I gave it away.
时间守护者 他们的位置
The Time-Keepers, where they are.
你想干什么？
What do you want?
不要 洛基 等等
MOBIUS: No! No! Loki, wait!
等等 洛基 等等
Wait! Loki, wait!
不要 等等 洛基
No! Wait, Loki!
咱们可以点烤土豆或炸鸡柳
We could do potato skins or buffalo fingers. . .
也可以去别的地方吃
Or we could eat somewhere else.
你为什么讨厌这个地方？
Why do you hate this place?
不是讨厌 是有点害怕
I don't hate it, I fear it.
你知道卫生部门
Do you know how many times
让这里停业了多少次吗？
the health department has closed this place down?
饮料看着还行
Well, the drinks seem fine. Mmm. . .
天啊
- -Oh, God!
冻彻心扉啊
Ah, brain freeze!
你知道什么叫冻彻心扉吧？
You know what brain freeze is, don't you?
我来告诉你
Here we go.
就是当你吸了一口特别凉的饮料
It's when you sip something so cold. . .
整个人就像冻住了一样. . .  我知道了
Brain freeze associated with coldness. . .  Got it.
别插嘴 我说正经的
Wait, I'm being serious.
冰水从上腭渗透进去 然后冻住了你的心智
So, it permeates the roof of your mouth and it freezes the synapses in your brain.
所以你的记忆也被冻结了
So, your memories are literally frozen in place.
-绝对不可能 -真的是这样
-That is absolutely not true.  -It is!
好吧 那做个实验 你在想的事会被冻住
Okay. Try it. Whatever you're thinking about will get frozen in place.
我要问你一个问题
I'm gonna ask you a question,
在心智解冻之前 你回答不了
and you won't be able to answer until the synapses have melted.
放马过来
Challenge accepted.
好的 问吧
Okay, ask.
时间守护者身边有多少守卫？
How many people are guarding the Time-Keepers?
不好意思 你说什么？
I'm sorry, what?
咱们交朋友多长时间了？
Hey, how long have we been best friends?
很久了
Too long.
说真的 你什么都可以告诉我 是不是？
Seriously, you know you can tell me anything, right?
当然了
Of course.
那你告诉我时间守护者身边 有多少守卫？
Why won't you tell me how many people are guarding the Time-Keepers?
好吧 那里有. . .
Oh, well, there's. . .
这个地方 我. . .
This place, I. . .
我想起来了 我认识这里
I remember, I know this place.
但是我不认识你
But I don't know you.
没事的 你就是有点累了
It's okay. You're just tired.
对 我可能就是累了
Yeah. I'm probably just tired.
电梯在哪里？
How do I find the elevators?
电梯是金色的
HUNTER C-20: They're gold.
《洛基》
所有时间卫士立刻前往军械库
ANNOUNCER:  All Minutemen to armory.
保护时间线
Protect the timeline.
所有时间卫士立刻前往军械库
All Minutemen to armory.
保护时间线
Protect the timeline.
我不知道 先生
MINUTEMAN: I don't know, sir.
所有时间卫士立刻前往军械库
ANNOUNCER: All Minutemen to armory.
保护时间线
Protect the timeline.
站住
Hey! Stop!
我有几个问题
A few questions.
你没别的事可干了吗？
Have you got nothing else to do?
真粗鲁
Rude.
你确定你是洛基吗？
Are you sure you're a Loki?
-你挡着道了 -我要找的就是你
-You're in my way.  -You are my way.
我本来觉得咱们可以合作
I thought perhaps we could work together.
但是现在我觉得你缺乏远见
But now I see you lack vision.
所以 你愿意一起来也好
So, either you'll come willingly. . .
不愿意也好 无所谓 你都要带我去找时间守护者
Or you won't. Either way,  that's how I get to the Time-Keepers.
天啊 闭嘴
Oh, God. Shut up!
嘿
- -RENSLAYER: Hey!
敢过来我就杀了他
Come any closer and I'll kill him.
动手吧
-Go for it.  -
放开我的腿
Get off my leg!
再见 时间犯
Goodbye, Variant.
电量已耗尽
-MISS MINUTES: You're outta juice.  -
不能用了
It's not working.
好吧. . .
-LOKI: Right. . .  -
把它给我 你不知道怎么充电
Give It To me.  You don't know how to Recharge it.
我当然知道 你又不是唯一的技术狂洛基
Of course I do.  You're not the only tech savvy Loki.
别那么叫我
Don't ever call me that.
-科技狂？ -不 是洛基
-Tech savvy?  -No, a Loki.
看来你是个魔法师？
You're just fully a magician then?
好吧 我的下一招 就是要让你消失
Fine. For my next trick,  I'll make you disappear.
-那是你的能力吗？ -你把我们带去哪了？
-Is that one of your powers?  -Where did you send us?
拉曼迪斯一号卫星
2077年
你这个白痴 这是拉曼迪斯一号卫星
You idiot! This is Lamentis 1.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what that means!
这颗卫星会和行星相撞然后毁灭
The moon that planet is about to crash into and destroy.
时间控制器储存的所有末日里 这是最糟糕的
Of all of the apocalypses saved on that TemPad, this is the worst!
没人能活下来
No one makes it off here!
小心
-Watch out!  -
对不起 女士 我没来得及看宣传册
I'm sorry, madam.  Didn't have time to scan the brochure.
不过我本以为你希望我死掉
By the way, I thought you wanted me dead.
我不知道你把时间控制器藏在哪了
I don't know where you hid that TemPad,
但是如果你完蛋了 它也会一起完蛋 然后我也就一起完蛋了
but if you blow up, it blows up,  and then I end up blown up.
那边
There!
-所以咱们现在是团队了？ -天啊 不要
-So we're a team now?  -Oh, God, no!
低头
-Get down!  -
我不需要你帮我
Didn't need your help!
你真奇怪
You're so weird!
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
你在试图附身我吗？
You trying to enchant me?
没用的
It won't work.
为什么？因为你是魔法师？
Why? Because you're a magician?
-不 因为我的心智太强大了 -好吧
-No, because my mind is too strong.  -Fine!
咱们真的现在要这样吗？再打一架？
Look. Are we really about to do this here? Again?
那你有什么建议？
What do you propose instead?
我不知道 停战？
I don't know. A truce?
听着 如果我们不能恢复时间控制器
LOKI: Listen, neither of us is getting off this rock
咱俩谁也别想离开这个鬼地方
if we can't turn that TemPad on.
你把它藏在哪了？
Where do you have it hidden?
-在我心里 -好吧 那我就把它挖出来
-In my heart.  -Well, then, I'll cut it out.
不错 真搞笑 太可爱了
Nice. Very droll. Lovely.
好吧 没错 时间控制器在我这
Okay, yes, I do have the TemPad,
要不是因为你一直要杀了我 我才不会走那么远
but I'm not gonna get very far if you keep trying to kill me.
你不理智是因为你需要我来充电
You're full of it because you need me to get that recharged.
这就是你救我的唯一原因
That's the only reason you saved me out there.
也许吧
Maybe.
是的 没错 也是原因之一吧
Yeah. I mean, sure. That too.
或者咱们也可以在这个破矿场里自相残杀
Or we could slaughter each other here in this abandoned mining shack.
-你觉得呢？ -我没问题
-What do you say?  -Good for me.
我谋划了这么多年 被你破坏了
The plan you interrupted was years in the making.
-那么多年 -好吧 知道了
-Years!  -Okay, got it.
只要我能打开时间控制器
And as soon as I turn that TemPad back on,
我就直接回到时间变异管理局 然后完成我该干的事
I'm going straight back to the TVA to finish what I started.
好
Good.
-到那时再杀掉你 -也许是我杀掉你
-I'll kill you then.  -Or I'll kill you.
你要去哪？
Where're you going?
这个卫星上应该有电源
There's power somewhere on this moon.
我们需要足够电量 在不同维度的时间和空间中穿行
We just need enough to travel through inter-dimensional time and space.
天啊
Jeez!
好
Yep.
那么计划是什么？
So, what's the plan?
那边附近有个小镇 你能闭嘴吗？
There's a town near here.  And can you shut up?
我不得不和你合作 但是我不想听见你的声音
Just because I have to work with you doesn't mean I wanna hear your voice.
好吧 那. . . 走慢点 时间犯
All right, well. . . Slow down, Variant.
你不知道咱们快死了吗？
What part of imminent death confuses you?
还有别叫我〝时间犯〞
And don't call me "Variant. "
对不起 但是我也不会对着一张 我自己的褪色的照片叫〝洛基〞
I'm sorry, but I'm not calling some faded photocopy of me "Loki. "
好啊 反正那也不再是我了 我现在叫希尔维
Good. 'Cause that's not who I am anymore.  I'm Sylvie now.
你换名字了 太好了
You changed your name. Brilliant.
这叫化名
It's called an alias.
听起来一点也不像洛基
It's not very Loki-like.
是吗？那洛基有什么特点吗？
Yeah? What exactly makes a Loki a Loki?
独立、权威和有型
Independence, authority, style.
所以你就自然而然地 去给那些乏味专制的时间警察卖命了
SYLVIE: So, naturally you went to work for the boring, oppressive time police.
我没有给他们卖命 我只是个顾问而已
LOKI: I don't work for them.  I'm a consultant.
你根本不知道你想要什么
SYLVIE: You don't know what you want.
是吗？那你呢？
Oh, yeah? What about you?
你这么多年的谋划 就是为了毁掉那个地方
Your years-in-the-making plan was to tear the place down,
创造出终极的权力真空 然后默默走开
create the ultimate power vacuum,  and then just walk away.
我可永远不会那么干
I'd never have done that.
是吗？好吧 我不是你
Yeah? Well, I'm not you.
咱们能继续走了吗？
Can we get on with this now?
好像所有人都跑了
LOKI: It looks like everyone already fled.
他们就算这么做了 也是白费力气
SYLVIE: If they did, it was in vain.
咱们还有多长时间？
LOKI: How long do we have?
12个小时左右 这里的情况只会越来越糟
SYLVIE: Twelve hours or so.  Things down here are only gonna get worse.
更多的陨石 然后重力地震
More meteors, gravity quakes,
当然 还有毁灭前夕社会秩序的崩溃
and of course, the collapse of society in the face of annihilation.
那能给时间控制器充电吗？
Could that charge the TemPad?
也许吧
Maybe.
我看了连接器 连接没问题
I'm just checking the coupling.  Making sure it can connect.
好吧
Right.
好了 给我吧
Okay. Hand it over.
可惜 我不会给你的 你得再努力点
Pitiful. I'm not giving it to you.  You're gonna have to try harder.
你也别假装什么〝技术狂〞
Then don't give me your "tech savvy" ideas either.
时间控制器需要大量能源 夜灯可没用
The TemPad requires a massive power source, not a night light.
蛮力不能取代策略和诡计
Brute force is no substitute for diplomacy and guile.
知道了
Noted.
你能飞这么远真是可圈可点
It's remarkable that you ever made it as far as you did.
不好意思
Sorry about that.
没事 我挺爽的
Don't be. I enjoyed it.
我也是
Oh. . . I did too.
我向你保证
But I can assure you,
虽然我的朋友像个动物一样冲动
despite my acquaintance behaving like an animal. . .
我们没有恶意 我们只是疲惫的旅行者
. . . uh, we mean you no harm.  We're simply weary travelers.
好吧
Sure you are.
你好 亲爱的
MAN: Hello, dear.
帕屈斯？
Patrice?
过了这么久
It. . . It's been a long time.
你还是那么美…
You're as beautiful as. . .
帕屈斯过去三十年一句好听的话都没说过
WOMAN: Patrice never said a thing that nice in 30 years.
你们根本不是旅行者 你们是魔鬼
You're no travelers, you're devils.
这算哪个？策略？
Which one was that? Diplomacy?
别说了
-Or. . .  -Don't. Just don't.
你们这些魔鬼想干什么？
What do you devils want with me?
我们就是想问一下 人都去哪了？
We just wanna ask you a question.  Where is everyone?
方舟号
The ark.
逃生船
The evacuation vessel.
那里肯定有足够能源给时间控制器充电
Something like that would have enough juice to repower the TemPad.
我们怎么去？
How do we get there?
火车站在小镇边上 但是你们不可能有票
Train station's the edge of town.  But you'll never get a ticket.
走吧
Come on, let's go.
安静
GUARD: Quiet down!
后退
Get back!
怎么回事？
What's going on?
方舟号今晚出发 我们已经排了好几个小时的队了
The ark leaves tonight and we've been waiting in line for hours.
好几个小时
For hours.
这有点意思
Well, this looks fun.
来吧
Come on.
我们不能靠打架上火车
We can't fight our way onto that train.
谁说要打架了？
Who said anything about fighting?
-你的计划里都是打架 -这个不是
-All your plans involve fighting.  -Not this one.
我要去附身一个守卫 让他带我们穿过人群
I'm going to enchant a guard,  have him lead us through the crowd,
要是有人找麻烦. . .
and if anyone gives us any trouble. . .
就让他开枪？
Make him start shooting?
然后呢 杀掉所有守卫劫持火车？
And then what, kill every guard and hijack the train?
要不要打架就全看他们了
Whether or not there's a fight is entirely up to them.
咱们按我的办法来吧
We're doing this one my way.
-看上去怎么样？ -看上去是个很烂的计划
-How do I look?  -Like someone with a shit plan.
这计划可棒了
-It's a great plan.  -Hmm.
跟我来
Just follow my lead.
-为什么我们不能上车？ -让我们进去 快点
WOMAN: Why can't we get on?  MAN: Let us in! Come on!
去苏鲁？这边请 先生
GUARD: To Shuroo? This way, sir.
让我们进去 妇女和儿童. . .
MAN 2: Let us in! Women and children. . .
他们只把票给了有钱人
They're only giving tickets out to the wealthy!
那咱们呢？
What about us?
您的票？
GUARD: Tickets?
嘿
Whoa! Hey!
我要把她带去苏鲁
Taking this one to Shuroo.
好的 票呢？
Okay. And the tickets?
上面有命令 带她上车
Orders come from the top to get her on this train.
长官 这个. . .
Sir, this. . .
有事吗？
Everything okay?
一切正常
Yeah, everything's fine.
对 我想起来了 总部今天早上
Yeah, I just remembered that headquarters radioed in
来电发出命令
their request for them this morning.
好的
Okay.
您的票？
GUARD: Tickets?
晚上好 乘客们 你们好
Good evening, passengers. Hi.
我不能在火车上反方向坐
Um, uh, look,  I can't go backwards on a train.
我从来不背对着门
Well, I never sit with my back to a door.
什么意思？两边都有门啊
What? There are doors on both sides.
赶紧坐下吧
Oh, just sit down.
注意 这根本不是计划
FYI, that wasn't even a plan.
真的吗？
Oh, really?
计划有很多步骤
Plans have multiple steps.
打扮成守卫上火车就是个动作而已
Dressing as a guard and getting on a train is just doing a thing.
你累了吗？你可以休息一下
Oh, you a bit tired?  Feel free to, you know, get some rest.
我不能在这种地方睡觉
I can't sleep in a place like this.
你在火车上睡不着觉？
You can't sleep on a train?
不是 身边都是不能信任的人 我不能睡
No. I can't sleep around untrustworthy people.
好吧 你是说我吗？
Oh, right. That me?
但是你可以小睡一下
But you feel free to take a nap.
你真聪明
Nice try.
我不会浪费时间寻找时间控制器
I'm not gonna waste my time rooting around for the TemPad
当有人教你正式的魔法的时候
when someone taught you fairly decent magic.
我的母亲
My mother.
她是什么样的人？
What was she like?
她是. . .
She was, um. . .
阿斯加德的皇后
A Queen of Asgard.
她人很好 非常高贵
She was good. Purely decent.
你确定她是你母亲吗？
Are you sure she was your mother?
不 其实她不是 我是领养的
Oh, no, she's not actually. I was adopted.
我是不是泄密了？不好意思啊
Is that a bit of a spoiler for you?  Sorry about that.
没事 我知道我是领养的
No, I knew I was adopted.
什么？他们告诉你了？
What? They told you?
-对 他们没告诉你吗？ -没有
-SYLVIE: Yeah. Did they not tell you?  -No.
当然 他们最后还是告诉我了
I mean, they did, eventually.
等等 给我讲讲你的母亲
Hang on a second.  So, tell. . . Tell me about your mother.
我几乎不记得她了
I barely remember her.
只有模模糊糊的印象
Just blips of a dream at this point.
我还小的时候 她会给我变这些小魔法
You know, when I was young, she'd do these little bits of magic for me.
比如把花朵变成青蛙 或者在水面上扔烟花
Like turn a flower into a frog or cast fireworks over the water.
看上去都是不可能的
It all seemed impossible.
她告诉我我也可以 因为. . .
She told me that I'd be able to do it too because. . .
因为我无所不能
Because I could do anything.
你想看看吗？
You wanna see?
还不错
Not bad.
她是那种能让你相信自己的人
She was the kinda person you'd want to believe in you.
看来她做到了
Sounds like she does.
她确实做到了
Well, she did.
你是在哪里学的. . .
So, where'd you learn to do the. . .
-就是那个. . . 那个什么？ -我自学的
-You know, the. . . Whatever it is?  -I taught myself.
-你自学的魔法？ -是的
-You taught yourself that magic?  -Yeah, I did.
那你就是. . .
What, do you just. . .
你就是进入他们的心智 然后投射了一些幻象？
You just go into their minds and project some sort of illusion?
这样会更简单 如果我. . .
It'd be easier if I just. . .
附身在我身上 拿走时间控制器 然后跳车？
Enchanted me and take the TemPad and leap out the train?
-不必了 谢谢 -那就别问了
-No, thank you.  -Well then, don't ask.
-好吧 -要香槟吗？
Okay.  -Champagne?
要 非常感谢
Ah, yes. Thank you very much.
我不用了 谢谢
No, I'm good, thanks.
那她的给我吧 谢谢
Oh, I'll take hers. Thank you.
干杯
Cheers.
敬世界末日
To the end of the world.
那个老女人选择去死 太可惜了 你不觉得吗？
A pity the old woman chose to die,  don't you think?
-她恋爱了 -她恨他
-She was in love.  -She hated him.
也许爱就是恨
Maybe love is hate.
我应该记下来
Should probably remember that.
怎么说的？〝爱就是…〞
What was that? "Love is. . . "
-"爱就是恨" -去死吧
-"Love is hate. " -Oh, piss off!
那么 说到爱的问题
So, on the subject of love,
这场战斗的最后 有没有个幸运的家伙在等待着你？
is there a lucky beau waiting for you at the end of this crusade?
有啊 还真的有
-Yeah, there is, actually.  -Oh.
在我穿梭时空在末日间跑来跑去的时候
Managed to maintain quite a serious long-distance relationship with a postman
我一直在努力维持和一个邮差的异地恋
whilst running across time. . . - -. . . from one apocalypse to another.
这样的魅力 谁能抵抗？
With charm like that,  who could resist you?
面对毁灭 人们什么都愿意
Well, people are quite willing in the face of certain doom.
他们肯定是
I'm sure they are.
这就是我继续的动力
It was only ever just to keep me going.
你呢？你可是个王子
How about you? You're a prince.
对方肯定是个公主吧 或者没准是另一个王子
Must've been would-be-princesses or perhaps, another prince.
两者都有吧 我和你一样
A bit of both. I suspect the same as you.
但是 没有什么. . .
But, nothing ever. . .
是真的
Real.
Mmm. . .
那么爱就是欺骗
Love is mischief, then.
不
No.
爱就是. . .
Love is. . .
我愿意再来杯酒继续思考的东西
uh, something I might have to have another drink to think about.
你知道我们要试图劫持能源吧
You do realize we're about to try and hijack
那可是这个文明唯一的希望
the power source to a civilization's only hope?
-我知道 -这可不简单
-I do.  -It's not gonna be easy.
咱们应该歇一下
We should rest.
好吧 你歇你的 我歇我的
All right. You relax your way and I'll relax mine.
她在歌唱 歌唱返乡
She sings, she sings come home
When she sings, she sings come home
你的制服呢？
Where's your uniform?
她在歌唱 歌唱返乡 她在歌唱 歌唱返乡
When she sings, she sings come home When she sings, she sings come home
-敬希尔维 一起干杯 -太棒了
-To Sylvie, everybody!  -MAN: Yeah!
再来一杯
Another!  -
你喝醉了
You're drunk.
没有 我就是吃饱了
No, I'm just full.
但是记住 我非常饱
But bear in mind, I'm very full.
你来试试这个
Now, I need you to try this.
和波特酒特别搭
It pairs very nicely with the Figgy Port.
谁有波特酒？
Who's got the Figgy Port?
关于波特酒你一定得相信我
You have to take my word on the Figgy Port.
你的制服呢？我们应该低调点
Where's your uniform?  We're meant to be laying low.
没人在乎 世界末日了
Nobody cares. It's the end of the world.
-我觉得有些问题 -没错
-I think something's happening.  -Yes.
那颗星星快撞上我们了
Uh, that planet is about to crash into us.
别犯傻了 我看见有些人奇怪地看着你
Don't be an ass.  I saw some people looking at you weirdly.
什么？
What?
你是什么时候变得这么偏执的？
When did you get so paranoid?
肯定是从我用毕生时间
It must have started when I spent my entire life
追踪你卖命的那些无所不知的独裁者开始的
running from the omniscient fascists you work for.
浪费了太可惜了
It's a shame to let that go to waste.
换个话题 我想到了个答案
Hey! Change of subject.  I thought of an answer.
什么答案？
To what?
你的问题
Your question.
爱就是一把匕首
Love is a dagger.
这把武器 可能远在天边 也可能近在咫尺
It's a weapon to be wielded far away or up close.
你能透过它看到你自己 多么美妙
You can see yourself in it.  It's beautiful.
直到它让你头破血流
Until it makes you bleed.
但是最终 当你向它伸手…
But ultimately, when you reach for it. . .
-它就成了一团泡影 -是的
-It isn't real.  -Yeah.
爱就是一把虚幻的匕首
Love is an imaginary dagger.
没道理吗？
Doesn't make sense, does it?
没有 这比喻太差劲了
No. Terrible metaphor.
该死 我还觉得有点道理呢
-Damn. I thought I had something there.  -
就是他
That's him.
-保持冷静 -没事的
-Stay cool.  -It's gonna be fine.
先生 我能看看你的票吗？
Sir, can I see your tickets?
又见面了 你好
You again. Hello.
票 当然 给你
Um, tickets.  Yes, of course. Here they are.
挺可爱的 不是吗？
Oops. Still, it looks lovely, doesn't it?
有必要这样吗？我可以解释. . .
Look, is this really necessary?  There is a simple explanation. . .
嘿
-Hey.  -GUARD: Huh?
你干什么？
What? Hey!
躲开
GUARD: Get out of the way.
扔得太差了
-Awful throw.  -
你能住手吗？
Oh, will you stop it?
再见
Bye.
时间控制器
TemPad.
好吧 我可没想这样
Well, that's not ideal.
-给我时间控制器 -好的 好的
-Give me the TemPad.  -All right. All right. Okay.
我摔得太狠了
Well, I did take quite the tumble.
你这个混蛋 你害死了我们
You asshole. You killed us.
没准可以修好呢 好吗？
Maybe we can fix it. Okay? Um. . .
你不是个正经人
You're not a serious man.
没错 我可是神
You're right. I'm a god.
你是个小丑 你在车上喝醉了
You're a clown.  You got drunk on the train.
-我是享乐主义者 我就这样 -我才是享乐主义者
-I'm hedonistic. That's what I do.  -I'm hedonistic.
我保证比你更享乐 但是不会以牺牲任务为代价
A lot more than you, I assure you.  But never at the expense of the mission.
任务？什么任务？
Oh, the mission? The mission?
你那光荣的使命？ 省省吧 你根本打不过他们
What, your glorious purpose?  Give me a break. You can't beat them.
好吧
Okay.
叫唤让你舒服点了吗？
Did the, uh, scream make you feel better?
舒服点了
Yes, it did.
你也应该试试
You should try it sometime.
现在怎么办？
What now?
-我不知道 你弄坏了时间控制器 -好吧. . .
-I don't know. You broke the TemPad.  -Well. . .
那颗行星要撞到我们了
And that planet is about to crash into us.
-是的 但是. . .  -但是什么？
-Well, yes, but. . .  -Yes, but what?
整颗卫星都被摧毁了 是吗？
Well, the entire moon is destroyed, right?
对 所有人都死了
Yeah. And everyone on it is killed.
-包括我们 -对 包括我们
-Including us.  -Yes, including us.
方舟号呢？
What about the ark?
方舟号没能出发 因为被毁灭了
The ark never leaves because it's destroyed.
咱们又没上去
Never had us on it.
那又怎么样？咱们劫持了方舟号 然后确保它离开这个卫星？
So what? We hijack the ark and make sure it gets off this moon?
我觉得这个想法不错
I mean, sounds like a good idea to me.
好吧
Okay.
真的吗？
Really?
我这辈子都没走过这么多路
You know, I don't think I've ever walked this much in my life.
那你这辈子过得不错啊
That's a pretty good life.
好吧 没经历过算你走运
Well, you're lucky you missed it.
我有个想法 你附身了我 是不是就可以帮咱们俩走路了
Here's an idea. What if you enchanted me and you could walk for both of us?
我就在潜意识里歇一会
Or I take a nap in my subconscious,
到了你再把我叫醒 好吗？
and then you could just wake me when we arrive. Yeah?
好吧 附身不是这样的
Yeah, that's not how enchantment works.
好吧 那是什么样的？
All right, how does it work?
这不重要
Doesn't matter.
我觉得我告诉你很多我的事了
You know, I feel like I've told you so much about me.
而我对你一无所知
I really don't know the first thing about you.
多亏了战术优势
Thanks for the tactical advantage.
你要用那个战术优势杀了我
LOKI: Ah, so, you want to use that tactical advantage to kill me
在时间变异管理局出现的时候
when the TVA shows up.
你不放心吗？
Worried, are you?
我得知道能不能信任你
I just need to know if I can trust you.
好吧
Okay, fine.
你想知道附身是怎么做到的
You want to know how enchantment works.
我需要和对方有物理接触 然后抓住他们的心智
I have to make physical contact and then grab hold of their mind.
怎么抓？
How?
取决于什么样的心智
It depends on the mind.
大多数很容易 我立刻就能操控他们
Most are easy and I can overtake them instantly.
另外那些心智强大的 就比较麻烦
Others, the stronger ones, it gets tricky.
我操控他们 但是他们自己也在
I'm in control, but they're there, too.
为了保持控制
In order to preserve the connection,
我就需要创造一个他们记忆中的幻想
I have to create a fantasy from their memories.
这你还说我是魔法师
And you call me a magician.
那个时间变异管理局的年轻士兵 她的心智很不稳定
That young soldier from the TVA,  her mind was messed up.
一切都被掩盖了
Everything clouded.
我得找到几百年前的记忆
I had to pull a memory from hundreds of years prior,
才能让她努力接受
before she even fought for them.
什么？你说什么？
What? What'd you just say?
在她加入时间变异管理局之前？
Before she joined the TVA?
是啊 她就是个地球上的普通人
Yeah. She was just a regular person on Earth.
一个普通人？
A regular person?
喜欢喝玛格丽特
Loved margaritas.
他们告诉我 在时间变异管理局里工作的每个人
I was told that everyone who works for the TVA
都是时间守护者创造的
was created by the Time-Keepers.
这太荒谬了 他们都是你我一样的时间犯
That's ridiculous.  They're all Variants, just like us.
他们自己不知道
They don't know that.
已经检票的乘客请到方舟号
ANNOUNCER: All ticketed passengers. . .
那就是飞船
SYLVIE: That's our ride.
距离起飞10分钟
ANNOUNCER: Ten minutes until launch.
最后一次登机广播
Final boarding call.
咱们能互相信任吗？
SYLVIE: Do we trust each other?
可以 你也可以
LOKI: We do and you can.
好的 因为这会很糟糕
Good. Because this is gonna suck.
保持冷静 已满员
GUARD: Remain calm. We're now at capacity.
请回家
Please return to your homes.
退后
Stand back!
-让我们上去 -让我们上去
CROWD: Let us on!
让我们上去
Let us on!
距离起飞5分钟
ANNOUNCER: Five minutes until launch.
他们要让这些人送死
LOKI: They're gonna let these people die.
距离起飞5分钟
ANNOUNCER: Five minutes until launch.
咱们得上方舟号 确保它能起飞
SYLVIE: We have to get on and make sure it takes off.
怎么办？
How?
-绕到后面去 -好的
SYLVIE: We go around.  LOKI: Okay.
请回家
GUARD: Return to your homes.
回来
GUARD: Get back!
退后
Stand back!
-你没事吧？ -没事
LOKI: You okay?  SYLVIE: Yeah.
站住 不许动
GUARD: Hold it! Stop right there.
走吧
SYLVIE: Just go.
这边
SYLVIE: Over here!
你没事的
MAN 2: You're gonna be okay.
不 不 等等
MAN 3: No! No, wait!
快跑
SYLVIE: Run!
小心
Watch out!
我来！
LOKI: I've got it!
快 我们走！
SYLVIE: Come on. Let's go!
咱们还有机会
LOKI: We can still make it!
希尔维 来啊
LOKI: Sylvie, come on!
根据漫威漫画改编
漫威影业 出品
《洛基》
字幕翻译： 虫二